

JAROSLAV KOTRBA



+420 604 724 303





Czech Republic, Brno



https://jaroslavkotrba.com

SKILLS

- R (DataTables, XGBoost, Shiny)
- Python (Pandas, PySpark, Plotly, Prophet, Scikit-learn, Statsmodels, TensorFlow, LangChain, Shiny, FastAPI)
- SQL (T-SQL, MySQL)
- Git (GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira)
- Docker (Heroku, GCP)

LANGUAGES

- CZECH (Native speaker)
- GERMAN (C1 certification)
- ENGLISH (C1 certification)
- FRENCH (A2)

HOBBIES

- Calisthenics (body-weight training)
- Interactive web applications
- Reading (also audiobooks)

SUMMARY

With over four years of experience as a data analyst and risk software developer, I possess a comprehensive understanding of building data pipelines for risk metrics calculation, machine learning models, and database management. I have extensive experience leveraging tools such as R, Python, SQL, and advanced data analytics techniques to drive business insights.

EXPERIENCE

Risk Software Developer & Analyst

Barclays

Oct 2022 - Present

Prague/Remote

- Credit risk metrics calculation and capital regulatory reporting
- Basel IV Securitization, RWA and EAD calculation with PD and LGD
- Creating data pipelines for internal rsageICOM model
- Developing and updating SQL databases
- Communication of requirements with users and business analysts

EMEA Mobility Leader & Data Analyst

Honeywell

Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

Brno

- Leading Mobility services operations within EMEA region
- Detailed Cost Analysis and Cost Optimizations in R & Python
- People leader (Line Manager) of EMEA Mobility Team
- Responsible for new contract implementation projects
- Process creation, maintaining, and improvement

Data Analyst

Honeywell

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

- Billing reports automation and optimization in R and Python
- Clustering and modeling of usage data across EMEA
- Forecasting of aircraft deliveries and retirement
- Risk evaluation of new mobility contracts
- · Database cleaning and maintaining

EDUCATION

Masaryk University

Master's degree in Economic Policy and International Relations 2017 - 2020

- Econometrics
- Big Data with SQL
- Calculation Systems in Statistics
- Statistics for Computer Science

Bachelor's degree in English Linguistics, Literature and History 2016 - 2019

• Semantics with focus on translation

Bachelor's degree in German Linguistics, Literature and History 2013 - 2017

Corpus linguistics



